MANSOOR IJAZ

Mobile# 0345-8521908

Email: mijaz107@gmail.com

Flat#05, Block#13, Street#132, PHA G-11/4, Islamabad

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I have experience of more than 8 years in telecom & management ranging from team management, network rollouts/deployment to operation and maintenance, project coordination and documentation. I worked beyond my job description and across line functions just to get things done. My main objective is to utilize my skills in a highly challenging and competitive environment that offers quality learning experience and collective professional growth.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HR & Admin Officer

GHC International (Pvt.) Ltd.

(Oct2020-till to date)

- Maintaining physical and digital personnel records like employment contracts leave database.
- Update internal database with new hire information
- Create and distribute guidelines and FAQ documents about company policies.
- Gather payroll data like bank accounts and working days.
- Publish and remove jobs ads
- Schedule job interviews and contact candidates as needed
- Prepare reports and presentation on HR-related metrics like total number of hires by department
- Respond to employee's' questions about benefits.

Office Manager

Gul Enterprises Mardan

(Sept2018-March2020)

- Overseeing the work of all office employees to ensure they work productively and meet deadlines and business standards.
- Monitoring office supplies and ordering new stationary, furniture, appliances and electronic as required.
- Managing office expenditure and budget.
- Developing and implementing new administrative systems.
- Reporting office progress to senior management and business partner.

Warehouse In-charge

ZK Brothers

(March2017- July 2018)

- Managing the efficient receipt, storage and dispatch of a wide range of goods from the warehouse.
- Looking after the transportation of goods into and out of the warehouse.
- Shipment loading and transferring.
- Working with supervisors to improve staff performance.
- Setting aside storage areas for new stock.
- Complying with all Health, Safety and Environmental standards.
- Developing and implementing SOPs for the warehouse.
- Facilitating effective communication within the team and across the site.
- Investigating any inventory losses.
- Planning future warehouse capacity requirements.
- Maintaining accurate staff attendance records.
- Ensuring products are stocked correctly and safely.

Telecom Implementation Engineer

Telenor Pakistan

(April 2016-Dec 2016)

- Commissioning and integration of BTS sites and transmission equipment.
- Participate in the acceptance testing of BTS, BSC.
- Verify link budget, BOO, and prepare snags list for the outstanding items.
- Revisit sites for the clearance of snags list for the Final Audit to USF audit team.
- Perform site visits during the installation, commissioning, and acceptance testing of the BSS and transmission systems to ensure that the quality standards given are fulfilled.
- Daily monitoring of hold-up sites and coordinate with the vendors so that work can be finished in time.

Telecom Implementation-Team Lead

IKAN ENGINEERING SERVICES (Pvt.)

(July 2012-March 2016)

- Developed ability to produce reports and presentations to a professional standard.
- Analytical skills to identify and resolve complex/high impact problems and make decision relating to implementation/ TRX expansion activity.
- Extensive traveling within the region.
- On site communication and co-ordination.
- Survey and Implementation for the LOS, Swap and Expansion Project.
- Coordinate with DT Engineer to resolve relevant issues.
- Responsible to prepare all TI documents including PAT reports to the regional team before acceptance of sites.
- Installation of equipment on site as per lay out and standard
- Installation of ZTE and LCC RMS and solar.
- Perform indoor & outdoor installation of Huawei & ZTE sites.
- Quality assurance at sites before PAT.
- Good knowledge of Link budget analysis and implementation.
- Integration, commissioning and media clearance as per the implementation plan.
- On site trouble shooting on end to end media clearance.

- Responsible for the on-time delivery of transmission Links and for obtaining all project quality standards through subcontractors.
- Responsible for the overall site supervision, acceptance and quality assurance of MW Links, BSS within the specified region.
- Reporting sub-contractor's performance and capability of handling scope of work to Regional Manager.

TECHNICAL TRAININGS & INTERSHIPS

- 2 months' internship as an internee at IKAN Engineering Services (Pvt.)
- 6 weeks' internship as a trainee engineer CM Pak Islamabad.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Contractor supervision/Quality</u>: - Supervised BTS/DBS indoor and outdoor sites per customer recommendation

<u>VSWR/E1 testing</u>: - VSWR and E1-testing by using site analyzer and BIRD Analyzer/Meter. (All Projects)

<u>Troubleshooting/Alarm testing: -</u> Troubleshooting of different kinds of alarms in BSS, MW and other power related systems and their rectification. (All projects)

<u>Documentation/Customer relations</u>: - Preparation of PAT documents. Good relations with the customer which yielded significant project benefits. (All Projects)

<u>Project/People Management</u>: - Optimum use of available resources includes persons and tools. (All projects)

GPS/ Digital Camera: - Excellent command on using of GPS & Digital Camera.

Software Products: - MS Office, Adobe Reader, LMT, BTSM, U2000WEB LCT.

<u>Presentation</u>: - Developed ability to produce reports and presentations to a professional standard.

Analysis & Evaluation: - Proficient in assessing data and formulating solutions.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Huawei WCDMA 3G Certifications 2014
- Huawei Network Safety & Cyber Security, QA & EHS Certifications 2014

EDUCATION

BS-(Electronic & Telecom Management) Bahria University Islamabad

(2012)

Reference will be furnished on demand